VIKRAM GUPTA

AWS –System Administrator MBA in Human Resource



vikramrgupta458@gmail.com



9623330402



New Delhi, India

SKILLS

Public Cloud (AWS) - Certified

- ⊙ S3
- o IAM
- Route 53
- o VPC
- SNS
- э ELB
- ⊙ Cloud Watch
- Auto Scaling

Incident Managements
Problem Solving
Adaptability
Collaboration
Strong Work Ethic

Time Management

Critical Thinking

EDUCATION

AWS CERTIFIED SOLUTION ARCHITECT-ASSOCIATE

May 2021

MBA /HR

IEC, Himachal 2017 - 2019

B.E / POWER ENGG.

RTMNU, NAGPUR 2005 - 2009

ABOUT ME

AWS certified solution Architect - Associate with 2+ years of experience in field of storage and cloud computing (AWS) which covers exposure to Design, Troubleshooting, Implementation, Deployment and Migrations; as well as 10+ years of experience in HRM & organization development function.

EXPERIENCE

TATA AIA LIFE INSURANCE

System Administrator, Delhi/ Feb. 2021 – July.2021

- Manage Amazon Web Services ELB, EC2, S3, RDS, SNS, Cloud watch
- Assisted in architecting secure VPC solutions in AWS with the help of Network ACL's security groups, public and private network configurations
- Create S3 buckets and also manage policies for S3 buckets
- Assisted in managing and maintaining IAM policies for organization in AWS to define groups, create users, assign roles, and define rules for role based access to AWS resources
- Create snapshot and Amazon Machine Images (AMIs) of the instances for backup and creating clone instances

MAX SKILL FIRST LTD.

System Administrator, Delhi/ November 2018 – Feb.2021

- ➤ Recognized as top 22% employee for exceptional & outstanding performance with G1-M1 Rating
- Assisted in configuring Elastic load balancers with EC2 auto scaling groups
- Assisted in implementing AWS solutions using E2, S3, RDS, EBS, ELB, Auto scaling groups, VPC, Cloud formation
- Capability to provide AWS operations and deployment guidance and best practices throughout the life cycle of a project
- Hands on experience in EC2, VPC, subnets, Routing Tables, Internet gateways, IAM, Route 53, S3, ELB, RDS, Security groups, Cloud Watch, SNS, SES and AWS
- Created users and groups using IAM and assigned individual policies to each group

HDFC LIFE

Deputy Manager L & D, Nagpur/ May 2018 - October 2018

- Assist region in due diligence, contract management with banc assurance partners & maintain strong partnership alliances
- Manage the existing product programs & do modifications/ renewals as deemed necessary & work towards integration with product team
- Assistance in driving the corporate and alliances partnership goals

CERTIFICATIONS

- 1. Graduate Diploma in Business Administration.
- 2. Diploma in Industrial safety.
- 3. Certificate in financial modeling and advanced excel.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth- 6th Oct. 1984

Languages- English

Hindi

Marathi

Pref. Location- New Delhi

Passport No. - H 1659285

Current CTC- 8,50,000/year

Exide Life Insurance Company Ltd.

Asst. Channel Training Manager, Nagpur / January 2018 – April 2018

- Established and designed training unit for branch staff
- Facilitated training sessions and taught about insurance and other financial products.

HDFC Sales Pvt. Ltd.

Sr. Sales officer, Nagpur / June 2017 – January 2018

 Oversee entire mortgage process including sales application, origination, underwriting, closing & Disbursement

ARISTA INFOTECT PVT LTD.

Business Development, Nagpur / January 2016 - May 2017

 Determined problem areas to recommend revised policies and procedures for the call center & monitor calls to determine customer service needs; also provided effective feedback, trained and utilized corrective action plans to meet operational objectives.

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT

Sr. Product Trainer, Nagpur / December 2009 – December 2015

- Travel to various branches throughout the area to lead new employee orientation & providing training on new educational management courses.
- Lead classroom & on-the-job trainings on topics including customer service expectation, corporate procedures, rules & regulations & sales techniques.